MINH NGUYEN (BRIAN)

Address: Morphettville, SA | Phone: 0401325943 | Email: minh.ndcr@gmail.com | LinkedIn: Minh Nguyen | LinkedIn

SUMMARY

Passionate data enthusiast with a strong background in data analysis and data engineering. With extensive experience in programming languages like R and Python, and proficiency in SQL, MySQL, PostgreSQL, IBM Db2, RStudio, Microsoft BI, and MS Excel in transforming complex data into actionable insights. I hold a deep interest in data analytics, visualization, and applying statistical methods to solve real-world problems.

KEY SKILLS

Technical Skills

- ✓ Programming Languages for data: Proficient in R and Python.
- ✓ Database and Tools: Experienced in SQL, MySQL, PostgreSQL, IBM Db2, RStudio, Microsoft Power BI, Excel, Jupyter Notebook, MS Excel.
- ✓ Additional Technologies: Familiar with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP.
- ✓ Others: Microsoft office, Azure DevOps, GitHub, Figma

Soft Skills

- ✓ Strong communication skills with attention to detail.
- ✓ Collaboration and Teamwork
- ✓ Quick adaptability to change and new technologies.
- ✓ Quick learner, trying to up to date new concepts and technologies.

EDUCATION

Master of Information Technology - Flinders University, SA

Feb 2022 - Dec 2023

Achievement:

- ✓ GPA 6.37/7
- ✓ Chancellor's Letters of Commendation for excellent academic performance
- ✓ Best Innovation Award the topic of "Engineering Management / ICT Management and Professional Standards" at Flinders University

WORK EXPERIENCE

Flinders University (Casual, Feb 2024 to present)

Casual Academic - Tutor for Data Engineering

- ✓ Conduct tutorial classes for the Data Engineering topic, guiding students through key concepts and practical applications.
- ✓ Provide personalized assistance to students, helping them understand complex ideas and develop their skills in data engineering.

Flinders University (Contract, Nov 2022 to Jan 2023)

Casual Professional Register - Information Technology (Canvas Migration Project)

Imported content from FLO to Canvas – Cleaning – up content and writing report. Peer – reviewing migrating topics and giving feedbacks.

City of Melbourne, VIC (Contract, Sep 2021 to Feb 2022)

Shop Front Vacancy Audit Officer - Economic Development & International

The Shop Front Vacancy Audit team is responsible for auditing 100% of businesses over a monthly reporting cycle as this is critical to the success of the program. To gather business operational data, helping to establish when business is open or reopening for community forums or communication platforms.

Baya Vietnam (Fulltime, Sep 2017 to Dec 2018)

FPT Telecom, Vietnam (Fulltime, July 2014 to Aug 2017)

HR Officer

- ✓ Conducted HR analysis including headcount, turnover, and recruitment metrics.
- ✓ Analyzed sales KPIs to evaluate individual salesperson performance and overall department and branch productivity.
- ✓ Conducted and analyzed employment surveys to measure employee satisfaction and engagement.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Successfully led and executed various data analytics projects, including data extraction and integration from multiple sources, data visualization, and critical analysis. For more details, please refer to my portfolio **HERE** or https://minhnguyenndm.github.io/portfolio-MN/